Francisco José Álvarez de Diego

Viladomat, 53 SA 3 • Barcelona (Spain) (+34) 657 10 79 63 • fjalvarez@gmail.com

Personal Statement

A customer-focused and analytic Software Engineer who can think "out of the box". Strong in design and integration problem solving skills. Expert in PHP, jQuery, Javascript, GNU/Linux and MySQL with database analysis and design. Drupal module and theme developer. Skilled in developing re- quirements specifications, user documentation, and architectural systems research. Strong written and verbal communications. Interested in a challenging technical track career in web-based application de- velopment environments.

Technical Highlights

- Strong back end developer with wide skill set.
- Experience in web performance and scalability, load distribution
- Object Oriented PHP 5 MySQL web developer.
- Specialized in high end, enterprise level Drupal websites.
- Managing and supporting multiple projects.
- Over 8 years developing for the Internet
- Highly adaptable in quickly changing technical environments with very strong organizational and analytical skills.

Professional Experience

• Splendia.com
Software Analyst
2012 – Present

- Code refactoring and development using TDD and BDD.
- Migration of PHP templates and layouts to Twig.
- Generation and migration of ORM model to Doctrine Entities, using proxies and repositories.
- Migration of Shells and Cron Processes to The Console Component (Symfony2)

Riplife, Bodog Europe

Barcelona

PHP & Drupal Developer

2011 - 2012

- Developed and maintained high quality web applications using PHP, Javascript, HTML & CSS.
- Built High-Performance and High-Demand websites.
- Participated in all aspects of the software development lifecycle.
- Built jQuery enriched back-end user interfaces to deliver a friendly user experience.
- Collaborated with other teams and get in touch with the latest technologies (Java RESTful web services, Ajax...).
- Developed Drupal modules based on Use Cases and high level Stories.
- Refactoring and optimizing preexisting code.
- Solving Continuous Integration faced need for all PHP Projects.
- Worked closely with product managers, designers, front-end developers and quality analysts in a highly collaborative environment.

Málaga

PHP & Drupal Developer 2010 – 2011

- Played the role of Tech Owner of the first PHP Project in the Company.
- Created the architecture and documentation for futures PHP projects.
- Developed PHP clients to integrate with the Java Services of the Company architecture.
- Building a new Deployment System of Drupal based on Ruby and Capistrano.
- Developed the functionality to push databases and assets across all the environments (*Content Synchronization*).

• Ingenia, Ingeniería e Integracion Avanzadas.

Málaga 2009 – 2010

Drupal Developer

- Integration with third-party APIs like Booking.com and Amazon.com.
- Maintenance and updating of Drupal modules from Drupal 5 to Drupal 6.
- Produced prototypes to communicate user interactions and design ideas.

Education

• Universidad de Málaga, U.M.A.

Málaga

Ingeniería Técnica Informática de Sistemas

2003 - 2009

Resume of the Dissertation: *GlueWeb: A Case Tool for Web architectural layers interconnect*Eclipse IDE Plugin developed to link different Web Architectures into three layers: User Interface, Business Logic and Database, through Driven Software Models (UML) and automatic code generation. Written in Java and LATEX.

Publications

• Expert in Drupal 7. Vol I

Forcontu Editorial

2013

Core Technical Skills

CMS: Drupal (5+years)

Web: PHP (8+years), AJAX, MySQL, REST, SOAP, XML, jQuery. Continuous Integration: PHPUnit, Maven, Jenkins, Bamboo

Other Languages: Java, C++

IDEs: Sublime Text, NetBeans, Eclipse.

Frameworks: Zend Platform, Symfony2, Codeigniter

OS: Linux, MacOS, Windows Version Control: Git, SVN

Software Development Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall

Languages

Spanish: Native

English: Professional working proficiency

French: Elementary proficiency